when the Mongols captured Rus' Yes, from the
когда монголы захватили Русь Да с
territory of Rus', that's where Kyiv is, in short,
территории Руси вот где Киев короче
Chernigov Yes, people didn't
Чернигов Да люди же не
disappear, there are very few of them left, there are still some
пропали их очень мало осталось их там
left there Well, you know, about five percent of
осталось Ну знаешь процентов пять от
what lived, that's the basis on which you
того что жило это на основании чего ты
say that Well, look, when they
такое говоришь А ну смотри когда на
attacked Vladimir, Suzdal, there we
Владимир напали на Суздаль там до
didn't reach Novgorod 100 km, thank God,
Новгорода 100 км не дошли слава богу то
but this campaign lasted one winter.
вот этот поход длился одну зиму
And you, from 1930 to
Так а у вас С тридцать вого по соро
1942, for 4 years, destroyed the southern Russian
второй год 4 года громили южнорусские
lands, but what are you talking about today, I do
Земли а чём сегодня общаешься
n't know. I'm just wondering where your
да не знаю Мне вот интересно куда ваша
pcu will go
пцу пойдёт
next. I mean, the church. Well, yes your new
дальше В смысле церковь Ну да ваша новая
church of the PC of the Kursk region But
церковь ПЦ Курской области Бут епархию
open a diocese of Kursk diocese of the Orthodox
открывать Курска епархия Православной
Church of Ukraine Everything is fine And what
Церкви Украины Всё норм А что
Oh [ __ ] Well you don't have I think I think that
[__] Ну у вас не Я дума я думаю что
it will be subjugated by the Catholic Church
её подчинить себя католическая церковь
then through the
потом через
Greek Catholic cool They they will announce
греко-католик прикольно Они они объявят
reunification with the
воссоединение с
Greek Catholic and Greek -the Catholic
греко-католик и греко-католической
Church will be raised to the level of patriarchy, I understand,
церковь подымут до патриархата я понял
uh  I understand that you don't understand at all the
ээ я так понимаю ты вообще не понимаешь
uh realities of the relationship between these churches
ээ реалии Отношений между этими церквями
Yes, between the
Да между
Greek Catholics such shady guys
греко-католические такие мутные ребята
They were recruited somewhere in the trash by non-
Их набрали где-то на помойке не
Orthodox hierarchs Yes, they They weren't recruited in the
православные иерархов Да они Они не на
trash it was Stalin who recruited the Russian Orthodox Church this one was
помойке это Сталин набрал РПЦ вот этого
recruited in the trash Listen, but for the sake of
на помойке набрали Слушай а вот ради
interest Who are the Greek Catholics for
интереса Кто такие греко-католики для
you these are the Eastern Rite Catholics What
тебя это католики Восточного обряда Что
are the Eastern Rite Catholics how
такое католики Восточного обряда как
did they preserve the Orthodox rite
сохранили сохранили православный обряд
But completely Catholic
Но полностью католическое
doctrine that is so and so and how did
вероучение то есть так-то а как они
these
появились эти
Greek Catholics appear Well they took it upon themselves to
греко-католики Ну взяли
strain themselves and seven bishops said
напряглись и семь епископов сказали
that there should be such-  then the Siki is the Polish
чтобы там такие-то сики это польская
Crown and they signed the Brest Union that
Корона и они подписали в Брест унию что
we agree on the Supreme Council
мы на ВС
and the Pochaev Lavra is
согласны а почаевская лавра
originally
во первоначально
Orthodox Well, like not Russian
православная Ну типа не российской
Orthodox, not the hands of the Russian Orthodox
православ не рук Русской православной
Church, it had nothing to do with the
церкви она не имела отношения
right Well, after the Mongol yoke it
пра Ну она после монгольского ига
arose like there with these monks ski Well,
возникла типа там этими монахами ски Ну
I have  in view of your type this is the Russian
имею в виду ваша типа это Российская
Orthodox Church it is not  has
православная церковь она не имеет к ней
anything to do with it Well, it does
отношения Ну имеет
Not because in Moscow for 150 years there were
Не потому что в Москве 150 лет были
Kyiv metropolitans Side don't look at the idea
киевские митрополиты Сиде не смотри иде
that look we opened churches there
в том что смотри мы открывали там церкви
in your swamps and not you here the Greeks
у вас на болотах а не вы у нас тут греки
opened a church in the swamps and you
открывали церковь на болотах и у вас
don't We opened for you the Greeks were here
нет Мы открывали вам греки тут были как
as you know the Greek advisers the
этими как знаешь советниками греки
Bulgarians are not even Greeks but the Bulgarians were the
Болгары даже не греки а Болгары были
first the first well the first 300 years all the
первы первые хорошо первые 300 лет все
Kyiv metropolitans except two were
киевские митрополиты кроме двух были
Greeks
греками
knew the Old Russian
знали древнерусского
language that is well not a chronicler Kem was
языка то есть ну не летописец Кем был
also a Greek so he was a
тоже греком так он же был монахом
simple monk No well I I'm just asking he m
простым Не ну я просто спрашиваю он м
was ancient Russian he was let's say I mean
был древнерусским он был скажем В смысле
ancient Russian look the concept
древнерусским смотри понятие
ancient Russian it was invented by
древнерусский это придумали современные
your modern historians ancient Russian he didn't
ваши историки древнерусский вот он не
call himself ancient Russian
называл себя древнерусским
though he was some kind of
правда онб каким-нибудь
room it's interesting to talk to you like this Yes
рум интересно с тобой вот так пообщаться
in history Look let's
Да по истории Вот смотри
take here a coin of Prince Vladimir Yes There is a
возьмём вот монета князя Владимира Да на
trident on it, I don't know if you can see it or not  this is
ней тризуб не знаю видишь или нет это
just original or it is printed
прямо оригинально либо это напечатано
these are these lines lines lines lines Yes
это эти реплики реплики реплики Да
lines here too trident ty here is a
реплики вот тоже тризуб ти вот родово
generic generic it turns out yes in Ukraine here
родовое получается да в Украине вот у
Rus had a capital Kyiv
Руси была столица Киев
Well let's say money
Ну допустим деньги
hryvnia coat of arms
гривна герб
trident question Well there was money there and kunas
тризуб вопрос Ну деньги там и куны были
and hryvnias Yes and hryvnias hryvnias rub rubles
и гривны Да и гривны гривны руб рублей
not rubles we didn't have rubles there were no
не рублей у нас не было рубли были нет
rubles - it was a part of the hryvnia chopped off Well,
рубль - это был часть гривны отрубная Да
that's why the ruble currency was the hryvnia Yes,
ну поэтому рубль валюта гривна была Да
they came up with a name for each chopped hryvnia
они каждому рубленой гривни придумывали
and then got tired of coming up with the name of the
название а потом надоело придумывать о
Supreme Court rub What does the word money mean in your
ВС руб Что означает слово деньги в вашем
Russian
русском
language
языке
Nice currency Where did it come from this word
Ница валюта Откуда пошло это слово
money can be from Tatar no and
деньги может быть и из татарского не и
don't look The thing is that this is a prison here is
не смотри Дело в том что это тюря вот
tenge For example, this one has Oy not hung up Oy
теньге Например у этого Ой не зависа Ой
just started O developed go in Kazakhstan yes,
только начали О разви го у Казахстана да
to this day the currency is called tenge
до сих пор валюта теньге называется
money this was a Turkic name
деньги это тюркское было название
that you Muscovites adopted that's why
которое вы московиты приняли потому не
you weren't part of the Horde Well, you were part of the Horde, you had
было вы часть Орды Ну вы часть Орды были
money and you were part of the Horde with us
у вас деньги и вы были часть Орды у нас
no money
нету денег
Well, how do you have money,
Ну а как у вас деньги
pennies Well, also something like some kind of kopecks
гроши Ну тоже такое как копейки какие-то
Well, this is pennies, one was called such, we
Ну это гроши одини называлась така нас
also have pennies Well, this is something like
тоже гроши Ну это что-то такое мелочь
some kind of trifle, here is ru, you are so
какая-то вот ру это вы так ти
dismissive, ses, there is a question When is
пренебрежительно сес есть с вопрос Когда
your country  Yes, it began to
ваша страна Да начала
be called a Russian state, you
называться русским государством каким-то
could say. Now it
вот можеь сказать Вот она сейчас
is called the Russian Federation, but before
называется Российская Федерация да до
that it was called the Russian Empire.
этого называлась Российская империя вот
In 1721, if I'm not mistaken, Peter I
в 1721 году Если не ошибаюсь Пётр I Да
proclaimed the Russian Empire. When was
провозгласил Российскую империю Да когда
it even called that? It began to be called
она вообще называла началась называться
Russian. Russian under Ivan II.
русская Российская при Иване II это
What is that?  year It's about
какой год Это примерно
1490 when he subjugated Novgorod
1490 годы когда он подчинил Новгород
Tver Ryazan What was the name of his
Тверь Рязань Как называлось его
state Russian state not
государство русское государство не
Russian state was not this now
русское государство не было это сейчас
your historians call Russian
ваши историки называют русское
state
государство
Show me don't even look Show me in
Покажи даже не смотри Покажи мне в
some documents treaties And so
каких-то документах договорах И так
on where it says Russian state
дальше где написано русское государство
or he  they took away the Russian state Yes, on
или он увели русское государство Да на
its stoves it says the Russian state  not
его печах написано госуда российский не
prince prince his title is Grand Duke of
княже княз его титул Великий князь
Moscow sovereign of all Rus' don't look at the
Московский государь всея Руси не смотри
official title what what is what
официальный титул что что такое что
is the title it's what he came up with
такое титул это то что себе придумал
True Well he considered himself that way Yes he
Правда Ну он себя так считал Да он
considered himself you know he is for example the sovereign of the
считал себя знаешь он например государ
entire Galaxy Well sovereign of all Rus' he is the
всея Галактики Ну государь всея Руси он
Descendant of Yaroslav still once again once again once
Потомок Ярослава ещ ещё раз ещё раз ещё
again look there are countless descendants there are
раз смотри потомков немерено потомков
countless descendants yes look it turns out that
немерено есть да смотри получается что
he came up with the title for himself in the 10th century it
титул он себе сам придумал в X веке
turns out yes 1400 what did you say he
получается да 1400 какой ты сказал его
knows maybe earlier well well it turns out
знает может и раньше ну ну титул
he came up with the title No well they themselves
получается он придумал Не ну они себя
they felt like the masters of Russia
они себя ощутили хозяевами России
the Moscow princes after the
московские князья после Куликовской
Battle of Kulikovo when they realized that they were not
битвы когда они поняли что они в
really some kind of appanage principality
общем-то ни какое там Удельное княжество
but the central principality of the country, that is,
а центральное княжество страны то есть
let's call it that, the Moscow
давай так оно называлось Московское
principality, it was not called Rus. Well,
княжество оно не называлось Русь Так ну
it was stupid to call itself Rus there. That's right, that's right, that's right, it is
это было глупо называться Русью там
it was not called
Вот вот вот да то есть она не называлась
Rus it was not called the Russian
Русь она не называлась русское
state it was not called the Russian
государство не называлась русское
principality Yes but  at first it was called
княжество Да но сначала называлась
Vladimir-Moscow then Moscow-
Владимиро московским потом Московско
Vladimir then Moscow so that
владимирским потом уже москов так то
is look Yes, you think adequately in this
есть смотри Да вот ты адекватно в этом
yes that is it was not called
мыслишь да то есть оно не называлось
Rus Well, you understand Rus is from
Русью Ну понимаешь Русь - это вот от
Lvov to Ryazan from Kyiv to Novgorod
Львова до Рязани от Киева до Новгорода
roughly speaking in a broad sense if
грубо говоря широком смысле если
we talk more more once Look at this as
говорить ещё ещё раз Смотри это как
you know says there
знаешь говорит там
eh Russia is there From Helsinki to Tuva
э Россия - это там От Хельсинки до Тувы
And then the Tuvans call themselves that they are
Да и потом тувинцы себя называют что они
Russians It's true Well, for example,
русские будут Правда Ну вот например
look now the Tuvans no Well, what kind of
смотри сейчас тувинцы нет Ну какие они
Russians are they Well, what Well, let's look
русские Ну что Ну давай так смотри
now why I want an analogy forgive
сейчас к чему я хочу аналогию простить
now for example Chechnya and the Republic of Tuva
сейчас например Чечня и Республика Тыва
are part of the Russian Federation yes
входят в состав Российской Федерации да
yes after the collapse of the Russian Federation
да после распада Российской Федерации
can Tuva say that they are Russians
может ли Тыва говорить что они это
so they do not look like Russians so what is
так они не похожи на русских так причём
similar not similar Well and the
похожи не похожи Ну и не распадётся
Russian Federation will not collapse Well, let's do it like that
Российская Федерация Ну хош давай так
Republics are national except Tatarstan
Республики национальные кроме Татарстана
Sakha and someone else there, here we have 21
Сахи ещё там кого-то вот у нас 21
republics, they cannot feed themselves economically, it
республика они экономически себя не
doesnt matter, it doesnt matter, Here  look
прокорм неважно неважно Вот смотри
Estonia for example fell apart it was a part of the
Эстония например развалилась была она
Russian empire So maybe now
Российской империи Так может теперь
Estonia can call themselves
Эстония сечас называть что они это
Russians if the Chinese come here they will
русские если сюда придут китайцы нас
kill us all Yes then part of this
всех убьют Да то часть вот этого
Russian population of Estonia there are
русского населения Эстонии их там
20% of them can proclaim themselves as the
20% могут себя провозгласить что они
heirs of Russia because
являются наследниками России потому что
they are the ones who stayed  had connections there with
они вот остались имели связи там с
Russia with the Russian people I understood everything that
Россией с русским народом всё понял то
is look come on So it turns out that
есть смотри давай Значит получается
the Estonians can proclaim themselves the
эстонцы могут себя провозгласить
heirs of Russia so Yes if
наследниками России так Да если на всех
they kill everyone yes And then nothing And then there will be
перебьют да И тут ничего И тут будет
China I mean if they kill And if they don't
Китай В смысле если пере А если не
kill us the Chinese will come and kill us all
перебьют придёт китайцы нас всех убьют
there
там
Nova Let's come China will destroy you all
Нова Давай придут Китай вас всех
Can Ramzan Kadyrov
уничтожат Может ли Рамзан Кадыров
proclaim himself the emperor
провозгласить себя императором
of all Russia and
всероссийским и
why Well, what does he have to do with
почему Ну ну какое он имеет отношение к
Well, with the Russians, let's say, like Estonia, but I
Ну к русским допустим как и Эстония но я
say that the Russian population of Estonia
говорю что русское население Эстонии
can call themselves the heirs of
может себя там назвать наследниками
Russia There they can have their own head of the community
России Там могут там свою главу общины
there call some kind of head of the
там назвать каким-нибудь там главой
Russian diaspora there come up with something like that
диаспоры России там такое придумать
Maybe there in the Baltics they can your
Может там в Прибалтике могут ваша
Russians who live Okay, let's do it
русские которые живут Хорошо давай давай
this way Did I understand correctly that, for example,
так Я правильно понял что например
Russians in Estonia Yes, after the
русские в Эстонии Да после того как
Chinese capture and destroy the Russian
китайцы захватят и уничтожат Российскую
Federation, they can proclaim that they are
Федерацию могут провозгласить что они
Rus' Yes, and they can claim to
это и есть Русь Да и претендовать
capture the entire territory of the Russian
захватить всю территорию Российской
Federation, I understand correctly, they
Федерации я правильно понимаю могут по
can rightfully do so Cool A than Well, that's
праву могут Прикольно А чем Да ну так
roughly what happened in the Mongol times of
примерно и случилось в монгольское время
Moscow
Московского
Look, that's interesting, yes, it turns out that
Смотри вот вот интересно да получается
when the Mongols captured Rus' Yes, from
когда монголы захватили Русь Да с
the territory of Rus', that's where Kyiv is, in short,
территории Руси вот где Киев короче
Chernigov Yes, people didn't
Чернигов Да люди же не
disappear, there are very few of them left, there are still
пропали их очень мало осталось их там
five percent of those who lived there Well, you know, five percent of
осталось Ну знаешь процентов пять от
what lived there On what basis are you
того что жило это на основании чего ты
saying this? Well, look, when
такое говоришь А ну смотри когда на
Vladimir was attacked in Suzdal, they
Владимир напали на Суздаль там до
didnt reach Novgorod by 100 km,
Новгорода 100 км не дошли слово
so that campaign lasted one
то вот этот поход длился одну
winter. And in your country, from 1917 to 1928,
зиму А у вас с по со в год 4 года
they destroyed the southern Russian lands for 4 years, plus,
громили южнорусские Земли и плюс
lets say, the same thing. Moscow, for
допустим той же самой Москвы вот
example, there is this Sergius
допустим вот есть такой Сергий
of Radonezh, his parents lived in
Радонежский у него родители жили в
Kozelsk, this is in the Oryol region, and
Козельске это вот Орловская область и
they miraculously  it was
они чудом вот
n't by miracle that they ran into the forest and were saved by
не чудом убежали в лес и спаслись
other residents who were few in number. And you
другими жителями малочисленны А у вас
don't have forests, you have nowhere to
лесов нету у вас вот вам некуда было
hide. Once again, once again, once again, you
прятаться бе ещё раз ещё раз ещё раз ты
were once in the Kiev region, first of all, in the Kiev region, in the Zhitomir region. Well, not as
был в Киевской в Житомирской Ну не такие
dense as let's say in Belarus there are dense
дремучие как вот допустим в Белоруссии
northern eagle forests
вот там северны орла леса дремучие
cool question question it turns out when
прикольно вопрос вопрос получается когда
under Mon Yes here they left no one and the
при Мон Да тут не оставили никого и тут
Mongols lived here it
жили монголы так
turns out Mamayev darkness and Yeva
получается Мамаева тьма иева
darkness Who lived in
тьма Кто жил в
Kyiv in let's say there was a
Киеве в допустим осталась
chronicle left paid tribute to the
летопись платил Дань
Mongols nanie ma
монголам нание ма
passed by Kyiv somewhere- then
проезжал мимо Киева где-то
1245 They went to the Horde to the Khan's father
1245 год Они ехали в Орду к бате у хану
and wrote that Kyiv was destroyed,
и пишет что Киев разрушен остался там
several churches remained there, including the St. Sophia
несколько церквей включая Софийский
Cathedral, the prince's tower on an island in the middle of the
собор Терем княжеский на острове посреди
Dnieper, and they counted 200 houses. What
Днепра и насчитали 200 домиков То что
was left of Kyiv and they wrote that there were
осталось от Киева и написали что там
500-700 people left there,
осталось 500-700 человек населения
which contains in
которое содержит в
slavery they write that something great happened
рабстве они пишут что состоялось великое
beating of
избиение
Rus' Horror this is you can dial
Руси Ужас это вот можешь набрать
there bli A question well question that is they
там бли А вопрос хорошо вопрос то есть
destroyed all the people there And how does it
там уничтожили всех людей А как же
happen that all these people multiply again so quickly
получается что все эти люди так быстро
another let's say when
размножить другая допустим когда
other cardinals were already riding in
кардиналы другие катались уже в
1521 That is it has passed don't wait it's
1521 году То есть прошло не подожди это
already very far away let's take this
уже сильно далеко давай возьмём Вот это
when the Lithuanian princedom Yes, this is the 14th century,
когда князивство литовский Да это 14 ве
200 years have passed and the same picture
вот 200 лет прошло и ту же самую картину
that a 220 houses were counted yards in
что а 220 домиков насчитали дворов в
Kyiv do not Wait What a big village
Киеве не Подожди Какие это большая дерев
would be 1324 look what uh here Kyiv Look
бы 1324 смотри каких э вот Киев Смотри
uh so
ээ так
here
вот
1324 year yes
1324 год да
Gedimin walks in
гедимин ходит в
Kyiv 1324 the Mongols in 1000 now
Киев 1324 монголы в 1000 сейчас
take about it captured look the Mongols
взять о него захватил смотри монголы
took Kyiv
взяли Киев
B4 gift
В4 даре
80 years the Lithuanians recaptured
80 лет литовцы отбили
Kyiv Well at the same time It was like they were in
Киев Ну при этом Это было как бы у них в
dual ownership with the Mongols wait again do
двойном владении с монго подожди ещё раз
I understand correctly that Kyiv was no
я правильно понимаю что Киев был не
more than 80 years it turns out under  the
больше 80 лет получается под
Mongols constant Invasions
монголами постоянные Нашествия
constant devastation and all that stuff and so on and so forth Did I
постоянные разорения и всё тако ещ Я
understand correctly correctly I understand correctly
правильно понял прально я правильно
that Kyiv was under the Mongols for less than 100 years
что Киев под монголами был меньше 100 ле
And what of this I understood correctly wait
И что с этого я правильно понял подожди
So Well you see let's say
Так Ну понимаешь допустим
And these Lithuanian princes wanted their own
А эти князья литовские захотели своего
pocket Kyiv Metropolitan and
карманного Киевского Митрополита и
in parallel with the Moscow one they
параллельно с московским
created their own but this Kiev
ещ создали своего но этот Киевский
Metropolitan for centuries
митрополит на протяжении веков не
was not in Kyiv but was in the city of
находился в Киеве а находился в городе
Novogrudok,
Новогрудок
I understand correctly That is, the
я правильно понимаю То есть там
situation there was extremely difficult to
обстановка была крайне тяжёлая чтобы там
talk about the restoration of Kiev, I understand correctly,
говорить о восстановлении ки я правильно
I understood that the Lithuanian prince Yes,
я я понял что литовский князь Да вот
these 200 houses Yes, like this stormed for a
этих 200 домиков Да вот так штурмовал
long time in Kyiv yes it
долго в Киеве да
turns out And why where is it written that he
получается А почему где написано что он
stormed for a long time all this is there The siege was The
долго штурмовал это всё там Осада была
siege of Kyiv was And so on And you
Осада Киева была И так дальше А ты так
described it so simply there 200 there 500 people lived
просто описал там 200 там 500 людей жило
that is look but the point is not that The point is that it
то есть смотри но суть не в том Суть в
turns out Kyiv was under the horde for less than 100
получается Киев был под ордой меньше 100
years how long was Moscow under the
лет сколько Москва была под
horde 240 240 2 by  mokva Believe me Moscow
ордой 240 240 2 по моква Поверь Москва
it used this time very effectively or
она это время очень эффективно
what Horde dream That is to say look Moscow
чтоль Орды сни Вот то есть смотри Москва
is a sut Horde State is a
- это сута Ордынское Государство это
continuation of the Horde
продолжение Орды
Horde No well there is such a version that yes we
Орды Не ну есть такая версия что да мы
have accepted a lot from the Tatars Mongol cunning
много приняли от татара Монгол хитрость
there is dodgyness but you are even more cunning
там изворотливость но вы ещё хитрее
dodgy us and will accept Let's
изворотлив нас и приму Дава давай ещё
look again, it turns out that Russia was
раз смотреть получается так что Россия
completely formed in the
полностью сформировалась в
Tatar-Mongol environment. And
татаро-монгольском среде А уже от русси
after 240 years, nothing was left of the Russians.
через 240 лет не ничего не осталось Нет
No, what are you saying? The
вы что ну как нет
Tatar-Mongols are a very strange
татаро-монголы - это очень странная
nation. They didn't care what kind of nation they were. then
такая нация
religions What language do you speak What
религии На каком языке говоришь Какая у
culture do you have the main thing is that you
тебя культура главное чтоб ты налоги
pay your taxes on time by the established date give And
заплатил вовремя к установленной дать А
even better there I'll
лучше даже там я тебе Я тебе больше
tell you I'll tell you more I'll tell you more it's not Tatars
скажу я тебе больше скажу это не татара
Mongols were in those days everyone was like that
монголи было в те времена все такие были
yes the Kyiv princes when they captured
да вот киевские князья когда захватывали
for example,
например
some kind of
морд какую-то там
creature there. Yes, they built their cities there.
сущи Да они там ставили свои города на
What language did the locals speak?  the population
каком языке говорило местное население
at all then no one was interested in this
вообще тогда это никого не интересовало
because there was no national
потому что не было национального
consciousness at all it was necessary for someone to
самосознания вообще нужно чтобы кто-то
pay tribute and everything he talks about
платил Дань и всё о чём он говорит
no one was interested in therefore it is not
никого не интересовал поэтому это не
only that why the population humiliated them in every possible way
только поэтому вот население их всячески
behind their backs and this word
за глаза унижала и вот такое слово
arose I kept thinking what is this
возник Я все думал что это
ozy no century word just eyes he has
озы нет века слово просто глазами у него
Here only money works only in the
Вот только деньги работают только в
direction of dough and more he has nothing
направлении бабла а больше у него ничего
he has no culture he has no there
нет у него нет культуры у него нет там
any religion there not that How
какой-то религии там вот не то что Как
the Turks came to the Bulgarians and to the Serbs and they
турки пришли к болгарам и к Серба и
started their tushis like accept Islam no
начали их тузи типа принимайте Ислам нет
such thing
такого не
happened ang pay money they especially
было анго заплати бабки они тем более
loved the Orthodox Church which
очень любили православную церков которые
these Kyiv metropolitans went there
там ездили эти митрополиты киевские
constantly to them then they treated them there
постоянно к ним то лечили их там
let's say one of the khan's was treated there and blind
допустим ханш одну там из лечили а слепа
I don't know what they treated there with nuno like there
Я не знаю чем там лечили нуно типа там
everyone was surprised what a cool metropolitan had
все удивились какой метрополит крутой
arrived Well, they constantly sang a song, it's not
приехал Ну смо постоянно пели песенку не
that look,
дело в том что смотри
uh, the Empire of Genghis Khan was Yes, it was quite a
ээ Империя Чингисхана была Да довольно
large state, it had
крупным государством имела связи и
trade and political ties with many,
торговые и политические со многими
for example, the papal  legates also
например папские легаты тоже туда
came there Well, what does this mean at all
приезжали Ну и что это вообще ничего не
Well, look at the Orthodox
означает А ну смотри православную
Church Baty Khan exempted from taxes,
церковь баты Хан освободил от налогов
therefore, when you come to the
поэтому поэтому когда ты приходишь в
Orthodox Church you see
православную церковь ты видишь вот это
all this gold because the rich princes
всё золото потому что богатые князья
dragged the entire Orthodox Church To
тащили всю православную церковь Чтобы
avoid paying
избежать уплаты
taxes, that is well well here is an example I found
налогов то есть ну ну вот пример я нашёл
such an interesting article the destruction of Kyiv in
такую интересную статью разорение Киева
1416 and the
1416 год а
Golden Horde
золотоордынских
constantly The thing is that look there were
постояно Дело в том что смотри были
raids for example Look in this in Moscow
набеге например Посмотри в этом в Москву
in the 10th century also Islam burned the Gerai at all
в X веке также Ислам герей сжёг вообще
simply this does not mean anything here
просто это вообще ничего не означает тут
if you look I will tell you more the
если посмотреть Я больше тебе скажу
French burned Moscow in 1812 and
французы в 1812 сожгли Москву И
that they ceased to exist because of this e
что перестали существовать изза этого е
Well Moscow there Russia restored And
Ну Моск там Россия восстанавливал А
listen how will you explain the Arabic elm on the
слушай как ты объяснишь арабскую вяз на
helmet of Ivan the Terrible and Alexander Nevsky
шл Ивана Грозного и Александра Невского
Yes, but explain how how can I tell you
Да а вот объясни как как тебе сказать
simply the
просто-напросто
Arabs made these helmets well our
арабы хорошо делали эти шлемы наши
helmets apparently they were not of such
видимо шлемы были не такого качества
high quality, they bought this helmet, it somehow
высокого купили этот шлем там он как-то
got to Rus'  stop stop stop probably not Well
на Русь попал стоп стоп стоп поди не Ну
look Lithuanian princes somehow made
смотри литовские князья как-то делали
normal helmets without Arabic script
нормальные шлемы без арабской вязи
Yes Polish Russians Yes in Kyiv
Да польские русские Да вот в Киеве
they made everything shorter without Arabic script
делали все короче без арабской вязи
for some reason Ivan the
почему-то у Ивана
Terrible Alexander Nevskaya Arabic
Грозного Александра Невская арабская
Maybe through the ardu a gift from the Horde
Может через арду подарок от ордынского
Khan I recognize you understand we we will never know the truth
Хан узнаю понимаешь мы мы правду никогда
but stop stop stop stop stop
не узнаем но стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп
wait you said yes what is there it doesn't matter
подожди ты говорил да что там неважно
why the prince of Rus how do they consider themselves
Зачем князь Руси как они себя считают
if you think that you are the heirs of
если вы считаете что вы там Наследники
Rus Yes why don't they
Руси Да почему они не славянскими
have Slavic Cyrillic letters but Arabic
кириллических у себя письмена а арабской
script if it has already been written
вязью если уже было написано
that maybe he didn't even understand that
что может быть он даже не понимал что
something was written there Maybe some
это что-то там написано Может какие-то
beautiful ones there, no stop, they weren't so
там красивы не стоп они не были такими
stupid, they understood perfectly well that it was
глуми всё прекрасно понимали что это
Arabic writing and the merchants were Arab and
арабское письмо и купцы арабские были и
so on, the
так дальше
message knows maybe and
послание знает может быть и
so not Well,
так не Ну
they go sza
они гу сза
v mi then thanks to
в ми то благодаря
Moscow if when the Greek
Моск если бы когда приехал греческий
metropolitan arrived from the rara of the Florentine Union he
митрополит из рара флорентийской Унии
announced that he was a cardinal I  that he
объявил что он кардинал И что он
signed all the documents about the un back then,
подписал все документы об уне ещё тогда
some year 1400 or something, and the Moscow prince
там 1400 какой-то год и Московский князь
simply stamped his foot and said he would be thrown into prison
просто топнул ногой сказал его в темницу
for this, he promised me that
за это он мне обещал что ничего подписва
no one would sign anything. That would have been the end of the history of the
никто бы На этом бы закончилась история
Orthodox Church, that's why we are
православной церкви поэтому нас так
perceived as something new.  that in theirs
воспринимают как зано какой-то в ихней
that we have ruined everything Horror yeah well
что мы всё испортили Ужас да ну
Bartholomew Bartholomew in fact I look
Варфоломей Варфоломей по сути я смотрю
at him he is already some kind of real
на него он уже реально какой-то
Catholic cardinal hidden he is
католический кардинал скрытый он изнутри
destroying the Orthodox
разрушает православную
Church from the inside also from direct fire destroying the
церков теже из прямой наводкой разрушает
Orthodox Church namely Patriarch
православную церковь именно Патриарх
Kirill And what did he do His demons Here
Кирилл А что он сделал Его бесов сво Вот
yes, that's true His idolatry is essentially his
это да Его по сути идолопоклонство его
Hatred of all living things his worship of
Ненависть к всему живому его поклонение
mammon Yes wealth and so on
мамоне Да богатству и так дальше На
What kind of things does he ride his, let's say,
каких он всяких ездит его скажем вот
this is same-sex love among priests
это однополая любовь среди священников
that flourishes in these
которая там процветает в этих ваших
seminaries of yours And so on and so forth
семинариях И так дальше и тому подобно
love But that's
любов Но это сильно
putting it strongly  Wow, I don't know, I don't know, maybe he
сказано Ух не знаю не знаю может быть он
loves luxury, but he's also like that, you
любит роскошь но он тоже он тоже такой
know, he spent his entire youth in the
знаешь он всю свою Юность провёл в
company  Metropolitan Nikodim
компании метрополита никодима
of Leningrad who
Ленинградского которого за глаза
was called a hidden Catholic behind his back he
называли скрытым католиком он из
never left the Vatican he was even
Ватикана не выезжал его даже там
poisoned there he died they elected a
отравили Он умер избрали Римского папу
new Pope Paul John Paul I From what the
нового Павла Иоанна Павла I От чего
second appeared and he was
второй появился и он
pro-government
проправительственными
That is to say he saved the Pope saved Well, how much
То есть он спас папу спас Ну на сколько
for 20 days He lived longer  And he was
на 20 дней Он прожил дольше А его
canonized at least for the fact that he
канонизировали хоть за то что он папу
saved his dad No, damn, Kirill really wanted to Kirill
спас Нет блин Кирилл очень хотел Кирилл
really wanted to but there is this Kuraev, he
очень хотел но такой есть Кураев он
wrote such a thing
написал такую веь
that this Nikodim
что этот Никодим
was terrible and all these
был страшным и всех вот этих своих
beloved mothers were removed from the church
любимых ма отли от церкви
or they were poured out on him
или ему зали
Yes, that's why For
Да вот почему За
what For  the fact that he is Kato he is very he is very
что За то что он Като он очень он очень
outrageous he would be better off
эпатажный он бы лучше бы как-нибудь так
writing it somehow with hints carefully right there
намёками аккуратненько бы писал тут же с
was a
Ларионов случилась
tragedy with Larionov one of Kirill's Favorites but he was
трагедия один из Любимцев Кирилла но его
really removed that they found a boy
правда отстранили что там нашли мальчика
Yaponchik there I am constantly telling you about
Япончика я тебе про и говорю постоянно и
him and now too  there they drove the rag Well,
его теперь тоже там погнали тряпка Ну
they admitted that somehow he had to be
признали что как бы он надо его
removed before he was banned But
убрать пока его не запретили Но он
now he is not  Metropolitan
теперь не митрополит
of Hungary And don't you think that Hilarion is
венгерский А тебе не кажется что Иларион
also some kind of Catholic
тоже какой-то про католический его
Catholics called him
католики называли
Uniates it's not clear where he came from Why did they
униатов непонятно Откуда взялся Почему
immediately make him a metropolitan and immediately
сразу его сделали митрополитом и сразу
make him the head of these
сделали начальником этим сношений этих
church relations That is, the one Kirill
церковных То есть это который Кирилл по
occupied before the patriarchate that is, well,
занимал перед патриаршество то есть ну
some kind of me  I think that it was imposed on
какая-то я думаю что его навязали
Kirill by some people. And what do you think? Is the
Кириллу какие-то А как Как ты считаешь
Russian Church an independent
Российская церковь - это Независимый
body or completely controlled
орган или полностью подконтрольный
by the special services? I don't know. Well, yours is
спецслужбам не знаю Ну пцу пцу ваша это
100% on the
100% на
priests. They are SBSH, they have all this. They have their own
священники пцу Они сбш они всё это у них
official IDs. They are all SBSH with us.
штатные корочки есть они все сбш у нас
all pcu epiphany like general of the SBU too
все пцу эпифания типа генерал СБУ тоже
yeah well epiphany is generally such a guy
да ну эпифания - это вообще такой пацан
from some village all sbsh yeah But
из какой-то деревни всё сбш да А вот у
you
вас
get the question is the ROC an independent
получается вопрос РПЦ независимая
Organization or is it completely
Организация или там полностью
controlled by the FSB Well not completely but
контролируется ФСБ Ну не полностью но
somehow there is some control
как-то есть какой-то контроль
naturally  what kind of No, well you know If there is
естественно какой Не ну знаешь Если есть
some bishop there, a
там какой-нибудь
high-ranking metropolitan, it is quite possible that he
высокопоставленный вполне возможно он
Somehow they maintain contact but ordinary
как-то связь поддерживает но простые
priests they are not connected with this in any way
священники они никак с этим не связаны
Yeah That is such an interesting topic
Угу То есть это такая тема интересная
so here is the question Is the Russian Orthodox
так вот вопрос Русская православная
Church independent in making
церковь самостоятельна в принятии
decisions or does it still have curators
решений или всё-таки у неё есть кураторы
and special services not Well look their position
и спецслужб не Ну смотри их позиция -
is to preserve their own  space on the
это сохранение своего пространства на
territory of the
территории
USSR that is well that is there is the
СССР то есть ну то есть там есть там
Ukrainian Orthodox Church But it is
Украинская православная церковь Но она
like with us our branch let's say so I'm not talking
как бы с нами наш филиал скажем так я не
about that look let's do it the Russian
о том смотри давай так русская
Orthodox Church Yes uh in their
православная церковь Да ээ в своих
decisions there decrees uh and so on there
решениях там указах ээ и так дальше там
when appointing
при назначение
uh  or excommunication from the church she is
ээ или отлучение от церкви она
guided only by her synod yes
руководствуется своим только синодом да
Or is there still
Или всё-таки этому
a certain Comrade Major to this synod who
синоду есть некий Товарищ майор который
says something about the wish the modern
что-то пожелание говорит современный
course of Russia and the church coincides by
курс России и церкви совпадает на
99% so the World Cup is different And in what way is it
99% так ЧМ отличается А в чём
different Well they have some there  I do
отличается Ну какие-то есть у них там
n't know a little bit at all, let's say,
чуть-чуть совершенно не знаю допустим
when Yeltsin was in power. And here,
вот когда был Ельцин у власти А у нас
let's say, in Old Moscow, the priests simply
допустим в Старо моско священники просто
scolded Yeltsin that he was leading incorrectly,
ругали Ельцина что он вот неправильно
that he was educating the youth incorrectly, that
что неправильно воспитывают молодёжь то
is, there in plain text  it's just that we
есть там прямым текстом прям то что мы
don't agree with this
не согласны с этой
government that's cool, I mean, do I
властью прикольно то есть я правильно
understand correctly that now the Russian Orthodox
понимаю что сейчас русская православная
Church supports the increase in the
церковь поддерживает поднятие
retirement age that
пенсионного возраста которую сделал
Putin did? And what does the church have to do with it at all?
Путин при чём А при чём здесь церкви
Well, that's the church's question. Stop. Well, you
вообще ну это вопрос церкви стоп Ну ты
say that it supports 99% of the
говоришь что она поддерживает на 99%
government.  Well, first of all, well, as
власти Не ну во-первых ну как
far as I know, the state does
бы Я насколько знаю у государства даже
n't even pay pensions to priests, I don't remember. I
пенсию не платят священникам я не пом Я
say, Look, you say that the
говорю Смотри ты говоришь что ээ
policy of the Russian Orthodox Church coincides 99% with the
политика РПЦ совпадает на 99% с
policy of the state. Well, with foreign
политикой государства Ну с внешней
policy. Well, let's say, raising
политикой Ну допустим воспитание
young people in a patriotic spirit. Well, how?
молодёжи в патриотическом ключе Ну как
church Maybe it is there to deny
церковь Может это там отрицать
naturally it will educate
естественно она будет воспитывать
Patriots stop stop stop for for this
Патриотов стоп стоп стоп для для це
preservation let's say preservation of its
сохране допустим сохранение своего
presence in the USSR space there
присутствия на пространстве СССР там
Latvia Ukraine Belarus Kazakhstan
Латвия Украина Беларусь Казахстан
naturally the church will advocate for this that
естественно церковь будет за это
is you understand And what
выступать то есть понимаешь А какие тут
conflicts are there so And can you explain to me about
конфликты так А можешь мне объяснить про
education of youth  what
воспитание молодёжи что
uh in Russia corresponds to church
ээ в России соответствует церковным
canons for the church look for the church
канонам для церкви смотри для церкви
in general there is no Elina or Roman it
вообще нет ни Элина ни римлянина
turns out or Jew So maybe for
получается ни иудеи Так может быть для
no nationality Well let's say let's
нет национальности Ну допустим
say there  all sorts of cadet classes
допустим там всякие кадетские классы
local dioceses also help with
местные епархии тоже помогают
financing so that there is, wait,
финансировании чтобы там то есть подожди
stop I'm right, I understand correctly that the
стоп Я пра я правильно понимаю что
Russian Orthodox Church helps
Российская православная церкв помогает
finance
финансировать
military classes Yes, but how does this relate
военные классы Да а как это соотносится
to some kind of Bible, for example, with
с каким-то с библией там например с
some
какими-то
teachings Well, damn, somehow  that you have to be a
учениями Ну блин ну как то что надо быть
patriot of your
патриотом своей
country, that's not even a hundred questions, okay, don't
страны это даже сто вопрос хорошо не
stop, just for the sake of interest. Yes, let's take the
стоп вот ради интереса Да давай возьмём
first Christians in the Russian Empire in the
первые христиане в Российской империи в
Roman Empire, so they preached
Римской империи так они проповедовали
to be a patriot of your
быть патриотом своей
country. Well, damn, how can I tell you? Well, the
страны Ну блин ну как тебе сказать Ну
first ones maybe weren't, but those who
первые может быть не были но те которые
came after  this is not like Constantine Yes, let's
после этого как Константина не Да давай
say we are the first, let's say we are the first after all
мы вот первые давай всё-таки первы Да
Yes, here are the Christians Well, first of all, the first of the first
вот христиане Ну вопервых первы первых
Christians, the Tuzla of the Roman Empire, that
христиан тузла Римской империи кра то
is, yes, let's say so again, that means,
есть да давай так ещё раз значит
uh, when you say that uh, to be a
ээ когда ты говоришь что ээ быть
patriot of your country Yes, it is precisely
патриотом своей страны Да как раз
Christianity that, as  here it would
христианство которое как бы за десь оно
be the opposite, international Well, you
было наоборот интернациональном Да ну
know, the Roman Empire itself was an
знаешь сама Римская империя была
international state, look, the point is
интернациональным государст смотри суть
not that there was no there We are there for
не в том там не было там Мы там вот за
Greeks for this yes that is look And more than
Греков за это да то есть смотри И больше
that
того
uh the first Christians from the point of view of the
ээ первые христиане с точки зрения
state were extremists
государства были экстремистами
were and agents Yes they were
были ина агентами Да были
these unauthorized rallies
этими несанкционированные митинги
And so on and so on until they
проводили И так дальше да то поки не
held they sat in basements and prayed
проводили они сидели в подвалах и молись
held like a meeting they were there in short they were
проводили типа собрание их там короче
also caught  like no well the meeting is
вылавливали также типа нет ну собрание
secret of course not and such tried to
тайно естественно не и такие пробовали
hold heads and tore off why this
проводить бошки п отрывали зачем это вот
look it turns out yes What and then suddenly the Russian Orthodox Church
смотри получается да Что а тут вдруг РПЦ
says you need to be a patriot of your
типа говорит нужно быть патриотом своей
country Where did this come from Well let's
страны Откуда это взялось
say Well let's say the sad experience of
Ну допустим Ну допустим печальный опыт
the same Roman Empire when it was
той же Римской империи когда её
captured by no one  wanted to defend the
захватили никто не захотел защищать тот
same sad experience of the Byzantine Empire
же печальный опыт Византийской империи
when the Turks invaded and the
когда турки вторглись а сами эти
Byzantines themselves hid and did not
византийцы спрятались и не стали
defend themselves and their state,
защищать себя и своё государство бить
many rich people financed
многие богатеи финансировали османского
this Ottoman Sultan so that he would capture
этого Султана чтобы он захватил
Constantinople. That is, this is already such a
Константинополь То есть это уже такой
bitter experience of other countries that it is
горький опыт других стран что как бы
impossible to give in there.  provocations to
нельзя поддаваться там провокациям
others there to
другим там
surrender this is such a soaked experience
сдаваться это такой это вымоченный опыт
you understand they still
понимаешь они всё равно Всё
Still they can't do it  the end of any
равно они не могут до конца любая
church Let it be Catholic Let it be
церковь Пусть католическая Пусть там
your pcu which is absolutely there when
ваше пцу которая абсолютно там когда
they elected Epiphany in the VSM Sophia
избирали эпифания во всм софийском
Cathedral they cut off the Internet and mobile communications
соборе отрубили интернет и сотовую связь
no one could like they were sitting at the conclave
никто не мог как вот на конклав сидели
not that not that when they
не то что не то что когда они же сбш это
turned off SBSH so so Well, let's say  when
с отключили так так Ну а допустим когда
Kirill was elected patriarch,
Кирилл избирали патриархом прямо прямой
it was broadcast live on Channel One, how he was
эфир шёл по Первому каналу как его
elected there, that is, live,
избирали там то есть в прямом эфире у
we have something different, we have a
нас друго у нас получается был
democratically open process,
демократически открытый процесс в
unlike your
отличие от вашего процесса
electoral process. And no matter how they try to
избирательного А как бы они них пытались
make the state last, they still live in
длиться государст они всё равно живут в
this
этом
in the state they understand
государстве понима
they can't say that you came
они не могут сказать что вот вы пришли
to this church and here you
вот в эту церковь и вы тут вот вот
completely abstract yourself from the fact that you
полностью абстрагируйся от того что вы
live in Russia or in
живёте в России либо в
Ukraine, that is, well, I understood well, but
Украине то есть ну никак понял хорошо а
how does the policy of the Russian Orthodox Church
как политика Русской православной церкви
relate to the policy of the Russian
соотносится с политиком Российской
Federation on import  migrants to
Федерации по завозу мигрантов по
increase the number of Muslims in the Russian
увеличению числа мусульман в Российской
Federation
Феде
and firstly, well, if a person arrived Well,
а во-первых ну если человек приехал Ну
legally, so to speak Let him work Let him
легально как бы Пусть работает Пусть
respect the laws of Russia illegals  now they
уважает законы России нелегалов сейчас
are being taken out of Russia in packs. Well,
пачками вывозят из России Вот вот за
I can't say for the last year. Well, my
последний год я не могу сказать Ну как
heart is happy when I watch, this is all that
бы сердце радуется смотрю я это всё что
they are taking out in packs. Thank you,
их пачка мо вывозят мы Слава тебе
Lord, because in the same Moscow there
Господи потому что в той же самой Москве
will soon be more of them than Muscovites, and
их скоро уже больше чем Москвиче будет и
what about this?  do it
что с этим делать
according to Islam Well, first of all, they
по исламу Ну во-первых с Исламом они
are trying to be friends with Islam so that we don't have any
пытаются дружить никаких там у нас
conflicts there, especially where the
конфликтов чтобы Особенно где там
Russians are, there live, like, Tatarstan,
русские Там живут типа Татарстан
Bashkiria, where they are divided in half, so that there aren't any
Башкирия где их пополам чтобы никаких не
conflicts And in Russia, let's say, over the
было конфликтов А в России допустим за
last 20 years, 10,000 mosques have been built,
последние там 20 лет построено 10.000
that is, can you imagine  now in
мечетей то есть представляешь сечас в
Chechnya in every town there is a
Чечне в каждой в каждом городке на
mosque designed for at least
стоит в мечеть рассчитанная минимум на
5000 people so look, neither in the
5000 маля так то что смотри ни в
Russian Empire nor in the Soviet Union
Российской империи ни в Советском Союзе
were there such indicators No, well, they
таких показателей не было Не ну они-то
live there in their republics there,
живут там в своих республиках там как бы
well, look here more  that the Russian
ну смотри тут больше того русское
population from these republics is
население из этих республик активно
being actively forced out. Well, I looked at this
вытесняется Да вот я смотрел Вот эту
latest census in Ingushetia, there are generally
последнюю перепись в Ингушетии вообще
less than a percent of Russians in Chechnya.  something
меньше процента русских в Чечне что-то
like up to 1%
тоже вроде до 1%
Sakha has become more than 50% Yakuts Russians have
Саха стало якутов уже больше 50% Русских
become less than 50% yes that is the dynamics of the
стало меньше 50% да то есть динамика
outflow that was during the Soviet Union of
оттока который был При Советском Союзе
the settlement of these
заселения этих
territories by non-locals is now the
территорий не местными идёт сейчас
reverse process They are leaving these
обратный процесс Они уезжают с этих
republics they are essentially being squeezed out more than
республик их по сути выдавливают больше
that  moreover, the population of these
того больше того население этих
republics is the result of a higher
республик ВС следствии большего
birth rate. And you agree
коэффициента рождаемости А ты согласись
that in the same Dagestan, Chechnya, it is
что в том же Дагестане Чечне
significantly higher because there are 5 children there,
кардинально выше потому что там детей 5
plus the Russians have one, maximum two, and it
плюс у русских один максимум двое и
turns out that all this
Получается вся эта
mass is entering the so-called original
масса заходит в так называемые исконно
Russian cities, now for example, there are St.
российские города сейчас например там
Petersburg, Novosibirsk, Yekaterinburg  and this one like him
Питер Новосибирск Екб и этот как он
Moscow let's say would
Москва скажем
not say that it is already a Russian
не сказал бы что это уже русский
city not Well look well there is such a tendency
город не Ну смотри ну такая тенденция
Well in Chechnya let's say in Soviet
есть Ну в Чечне допустим в советское
times in Chechnya there lived a million Chechens there were
время в Чечне жило миллион чеченцев там
somewhere around 900,000 Chechens and half a million
где-то 900.000 чеченцев и полмиллиона
Russians and out of this half a million
русских и из этого полмиллиона тебя
30,000 Ukrainians identified you  so that
идентифицировали 30.000 украинцев чтоб
you this yes these were not locals yes when you
ты это да это были неместные да когда
came  Dudayev, that's when Dudayev was Yes, by the day or so
пришёл Дудаев вот при дудаеве Да к дено
from That's from this half a million
че году от Это от этого полумиллиона
Russians and there are 60,000 Russians left,
русских а русских осталось
yes, these are not locals, not
60.000 ун вот да это не местные не
locals The Soviet Union is specially
местные Советский Союз туда специально
brought there, there is another
навозиш там другое
economy, not an economy, you understand, when a
экономика не экономика понимаешь когда
bunch of hungry healthy
куча голодных здоровых
men they find an economy, for example,
мужиков они найдут экономику например
they are all markets  they will keep you in Russia and
они все рынки будут держать в России и
so on Yes, because you are not
так дальше Да потому что ты не
organized They are organized, they
организованный Они организованы они
will give it to Russian guys like you and
дадут таким как ты русским пацанам и
will hold the market And you will not
будет держать рынок А вы ничего не
do anything, look Now the whole
сделаете посмотри Сейчас весь
Krasnodar region, in fact, yes, it is not under the
Краснодарский край по сути да он не под
Russians there are Armenians, Dagestanis, Chechens And
русскими там армяне дагестанцы чечен И
so on  Well, so or not de facto yes
так дальше Ну так или нет дефакто да
maybe yes everything is normal They are generally the
может быть да всё норме Они в общем-то
lesser evil these are Christians Some
это меньшее зло это христиане Какие
kind of Georgians are Christians but that's not what I'm talking about
никакие и грузины христиане но не я не о
I'm talking about the fact that Russians Russians as a
том Я о том что русских русских как
social stratum from business and from this
социальный слой из бизнеса и с этого
the rise was removed from Krasnodar  edges for
повы сняли с Краснодарского края уже
a long time Well, damn, what can you do? Moreover,
давно Ну блин а что поделать больше того
now look,
теперь смотри
active infiltration
активная инфильтрация
of non-Russians has been going on for more than a decade.  different power structures
нерусских в силовые разные структуры
now how many police
сейчас сколько там полицейских
investigators of all sorts are there in the Investigative
следователей всяких там в следственном
Committee And so on not only non-
комитете И так дальше не то что не
Russians but even non-Russians of their
русских А даже не россиян вание своих
comrades once I once wrote that
товарищей один раз я один раз писал у
money was stolen from my card and I
меня деньги похитили с карточки и вот
wrote a statement and saw such a non-Russian
такого не русского писал заявление и
how does it work that in general what is
видел как он работает что в общем-то что
there
там
that is Well, it is clear that a person is appointed to
то есть Ну понятно человек поставлен для
solve their own questions Look at these
решения своих для вопро Смотри вот эти
ethnic groups Yes, they appoint their
этнические группировки Да ставят своих
people In order to protect their own
людей Для того для крышевание своих же
groups Yes And milking people like you
группировок Да И доения вот таких как ты
conditionally Yes, that is, you  for them it's a
условно Да вот то есть ты для них это
food source you and those like you Yes sooner
кормовая база ты и такие как ты Да рано
or later they will have to reconsider this
или поздно им придётся пересмотреть эту
policy it won't work in my opinion the point of
политику не получится по-моему точка
no return has already passed by the way look I
невозврата уже прошла кстати смотри
recommend you watch here is
рекомендую тебе посмотреть вот есть
such a book
такая кни
Janusz Bugajski the state cannot be an
Януш бугайский не спроможна держава
instruction manual on shmani Russia this is
инструкция по шмани России это
an instruction manual on dismemberment  Russia has very
инструкция по расчленения России очень
good analytics, this CIA employee
хорошая аналитика это этот работник ЦРУ
Janusz Bugajski wrote it in 2 VM year it
Януш бугайский написал она в 2 ВМ году
came out in English you can find it on the
вышла на английском языке можешь её в
Internet there count here in
интернете там найти посчитать у нас на
Ukrainian it was translated in t fourth
украинском она переведена в ть четвёртом
year  a very good analysis has been released between
году выпущена очень хороший анализ между
ethnic problems in the Russian
этнических проблем в Российской
Federation territorial
Федерации территориальных
regional conflict Elite conflict
региональных конфликта Элит конфликт
Well look they won't
Ну смотри отсоединиться они не
secede because they are stupidly
отсоединять потому что они себя тупо не
useless they have a very weak in them in the bunker
проко они у них очень сла в них вбункере
look for example Latvia Lithuania Estonia Yes it is
смотри например Латвия Литва Эстония Да
better to incorporate than the Leningrad region neighboring
лучше чем Ленинградская область соседняя
so conditionally  and Pskov as well and here
так условно и Псковская также и тут
look the Caucasus will be taken under
смотри Кавказ будет взят под протекторат
NATO protectorate Yes investments will be poured in
НАТО Да будет вливаться туда инвестиции
Yes because Iran and Russia are there that is
Да потому что там Иран и Россия то есть
access to the Caspian NATO NATO is already look
выход на Каспий НАТО НАТО уже смотри
almost present in Armenia you can
почти присутствуют в Армении можно
say so already all facts Armenia
сказать так уже всё факти Армению
is being torn to pieces
раздирают на куски
not Armenia
не Армению
is being torn to pieces  once again it is not Armenia that is being torn to
раздирают ещ раз не Армению раздирают на
pieces but Russia is leaving Armenia and
куски а Россия выходит из Армении и
another Guarantor is entering there, the one that is
входит туда другой Гарант тот который
strong Let there be NATO and that's all you
сильный Да будет НАТО вот и всё
understand Armenia and Georgia have an
понимаешь Вот у Армении Грузии будущее
absolutely bleak future and even
абсолютно безрадостное и даже сказал
Black said Why sooner or later
Чёрное Почему что рано или поздно там
Sultan Argan will simply turn them into  the
вот Султан арган их просто превратит
Emir of
свои Эмира
Syria is somewhere there. He also got into
Сирии где-то там Он ещё залез там в
Kurdistan there.  he climbs into Iraq there, he
Курдистан лезет там в иракский также он
will also climb there and establish Turkish power,
туда залезет и установит турецкую власть
all these Armenians and Georgians will run, you know,
все эти армяне и грузины побегут знаешь
where to save themselves, to Russia, and there, and
куда спасаться в Россию да и там и
only those who run to Russia
только те которые убегут в Россию они
will be able to preserve their language and culture in
смогут сохранить свой язык и культуру в
other countries. Well, maybe Europe, but
других стран Ну может быть Европу но
Europe is not  rich who have money
Европу пот богатую кого есть деньги
to buy housing there there get a
чтобы купить жильё там там устроиться на
job who knows well there
работу которые хорошо знает там
some English or French
какой-нибудь английский либо французский
German languages understood Pony And all the
немецкий языки понял Поня А все
rest they will just be
остальные они просто их будут
there well let's say kakh Nagorno here
там ну вот допустим ках Нагорный вот
Nagorno Karabakh Aliyev said Armenians
Нагорный Карабах Алиев сказал армяне
Let them stay they will live  in
Пусть остаются они будут жить в
Azerbaijan 99 Armenians gathered their
Азербайджане 99 армян собрались свои
belongings what they could and left Yes
манатки что смогли собрать и уехали Да
they didn't want to and left And what about me
они не захотели и уехали И что да меня У
I have an Armenian friend she is already over
меня есть знакомая армянка ей уже там за
80 years old there she is the same as look and I will
80 лет она так же как смотри а я я тебе
tell you more for everything for everything for everything
больше скажу за все за все за все
wait for all these years the Azerbaijanis
подожди за все эти года азербайджанцы
remained in Armenia also the ones who left with
остались в Армении также поуехавшие
stones they
камнями они
am when there were ethnic conflicts in the
ам когда были этнические конфликты в
late twenties between Armenians and Azerbaijanis
конце тых между армянами азербайджанцами
Yes there were in these and how  they were Armenians they
Да были и в этих и как они армяне были
beat up Azerbaijanis where they could where they
лупили азербайджанцев где могли где
could Azerbaijan it was
могли Азербайджан это было
ethnic hatred it has been in centuries just in
этник ненависть она в веках просто на в
centuries absolutely Just like Ukrainians and
веках абсолютно Так же как у украинцев и
Russians have hatred in centuries like absolutely
русских ненависть в веках типа абсолютно
and what well now it has become not up to this
и что ну она сейчас стало не до этого
nothing was let's say because it is not
ничего не было скажем так как не было
everything was just
всё было просто
like it was burning burning like here you are burning there
типа горело горело типа вот и вы горила
was just there was Western Ukraine
была просто была Западная Украина
which hated Russia and which
которая ненавидела Россию и которая
taught hatred which taught
научила ненависти которая научила
hatred to the Armed Forces the rest of Ukraine
ненависти ВС остальную Украину
that's what good awaits in this paradigm of
вот и что ждёт хорошего в этой парадигме
Ukraine future Who is considered the founder of
Украины будуще Кто считается основателем
integral Ukrainian
интегрального украинского
nationalism Well, I don't know  Well, Dmitry
национализма Ну я не знаю Ну Дмитрий
Dontsov is not Dmitry Dontsov But Dontsov
донцо не Дмитрий Донцов А вот Донцов
yes yes yes where is he from somewhere in Russia
дада да откуда он откуда-то из России
I think from Rostov or something Taganrok
кажется из Ростова что ли таганрок
something like that Yes yes yes
что-то такое Да вот вот
Mikhnovsky yes from Kharkov and so on that
да михновский да с Харькова и так дальше
is this is a Soviet myth Soviet myth
то есть это Советский миф Советский миф
that Nationalism is where  -then from Western
что Национализм это где-то с Западной
Ukraine no, it is precisely nationalism that
Украины нет как раз именно э национализм
has spread as ethnicity on the
раздвинул вот как этнический ещё на
territory of both the Russian Empire and the
территории и Российской империи и на
Austro-Hungarian Empire, that
территории австро-венгерской империи то
is, the Ukrainians -  it was a divided
есть украинцы - это было разделённая
nation between some Empire like
нация между некоторыми Империя как
now the Kurds in Iraq in Syria for example and
сейчас курды в Ираке в Сирии например и
in this and
в этом и
in Turkey there you had in Kharkov the
в Турции там у вас в Харькове был
first university the very first in Ukraine 1804
первый самый первый в Украине 1804 год
founded and for the first 70 years there taught
основан и первые лет 70 там преподавали
Poles and Jews
поляки и евреи
and Latin or Polish  in Kharkov
и латыне либо на польском в Харькове Да
And people who got an education there did
и люди которые получили там образование
not get a special training and hatred for
не получили особую закалку и ненависть к
ROSI and in Kiev there is the Shevchenko
РОСИ и в Киеве там Шевченковский
Institute also the same Pony Pony In short,
институт тоже такой же Поня Поня Короче
look I have
смотри я
this thing of yours what is it in
те Вот вот эту твою штуку что это на
Western Ukraine only hated
Западной Украина только ненавидела
Russia and I will say more  in Western
Россию да и я больше скажу на э Западной
Ukraine until the 9th year Yes, there were
Украине до 9го года Да были ещё даже не
some of these Muscovite people somewhere before the beginning of the First World War Yes, there were some of these Muscovite people
мировой Да были какие-то москвофилы эти
Because here you think that Austria is
Потому что тут считаешь что Австрия они
being oppressed there And these are the Slavs
типа там ущемляют А это типа там славяне
And so on and so forth
И так дальше
after  The First World War somehow it
во после Первой мировой очень как-то это
all passed very quickly everyone saw what it was
всё быстро прошло все увидели что такое
and in short everyone became not No, well, as if they were
и короче всем стало не Не ну как бы
offended for leaving Lu
за обиделись за то что ушли из лю ещё
once again like that  look, uh, that this is Western
раз так смотри ээ то что это Западная
Ukraine. Yes, they were some kind of nationalists who didn't
Украина Да они какие-то националисты не
like Russia. It's not true.
любили Россию Это неправда не любила
The whole of Ukraine didn't like Russia. If we look
Россию вся Украина если мы посмотрим
after 1917. Well, when there was a revolution
после 1917 года Ну когда была революция
in Russia, we had a Ukrainian People's Republic formed on
в России у нас образовалась ээ на
the territory of the former Russian Empire,
территории бывшей Российской империи
on the
украинская народная республика на
territory of Austria.  - the Hungarian Empire,
территории австро-венгерской империи
which also sank into oblivion, the
которая тоже канула в лету образовалась
Western Ukrainian People's Republic was formed.
западно-украинская народная республика
Yes, these are two
Да это две
independent political entities.
независимых два политических образования
Yes, with their own national aspirations
Да со своими национальными стремлениями
for the Independence of the Ukrainian people. Yes, they, uh,
к Независимости украинского народа Да
for centuries, it turns out, for 300 years
ээ столетиями получается там лет 300
plus, even lived in different states,
плюс даже жили в разных государствах та
in the Russian Empire, in  it
в Российской империи та в
turns out Austro-Hungarian well there in
австро-венгерской получается ну там та в
Poland And then when Poland went away then in
Польше А потом когда Польша отошла то в
Austro-Hungarian and they came to
австро-венгерской и они пришли к вот
this nationalism Yes what should we
этому национализм Да что мы должны
do state of the Ukrainian nation there
сделать государство украинской нации там
even Skoropadsky said that
даже скоропадский говорил что
Central Ukraine differs from
Центральная Украина отличается от
Western that Central in general-  then
Западной то что Центральная в общем-то
they are more friendly towards Russia
более там настроена дружелюбно к России
than the West no no Look no no that
чем Западная не нет Смотри не так нет то
firstly it is definitely different
что во-первых отличается однозначно
because the territories  who spent
потому что территории которые пробыли
300 years in different states Yes,
300 лет в разных государствах Да
they are connected to different economic
они связаны на разные экономические
centers, different political centers, different
центры на разные политические на разные
cultures This is obvious Yes, no one even
культур Это очевидно Да тут никто даже
argues here Yes, naturally, it is the same as For
не спорит Да Естественно что так же как
example, if we take the collapse of the
Например если мы возьмём развал
Soviet Union Yes, all the same,
Советского Союза Да всё равно из Украины
many people from Ukraine traveled there where - then already to study in
многие там ездили где-то уже учиться в
Russia or to work in Russia, that is, these
Россию или работать в Россию то есть эти
connections remained, they do not break so quickly.
связи оставались они так быстро не
And so it was in 1917, there
рвутся Да также и так 917 год очень
were a lot of those who were oriented towards St.
много было те которые ориентированы на
Petersburg. Well, and then, towards Moscow.
Петербург были Ну а потом Да на Москву
It is obvious that such were so
Это очевидно что такие были так потому
because they already had a concept of some kind of
что у них уже был концепт какой-то
interaction with this territory,
взаимодействия с этой территорией вот
okay Well, let's say your Ukrainian
О'кей Ну вот допустим вашу украинскую
this People's Republic was proclaimed in the
эту народную Республику провозгласили в
circus on Nikolaevskaya Street in Kyiv in the
цирке на Николаевской улице в Киеве в
circus No, no, in the circus it was
цирке Нет нет нет в цирке это
Skoropadsky no, in the circus it was Skoropadsky who
скоропадский нет в цирк это скоропадский
proclaimed it it was eat Khleborobov
провозгласил его это съе Хлеборобов
Khleborobov is Skoropadsky, look, it was the UPR,
Хлеборобов это скоропадский это смотри
don't look, it was the UPR, but
УНР не смотри было УНР а провозгласил
Skoropadsky proclaimed it, like, they also joked
скоропадский типа его ещё типа шутили
that it wasn't real  get it's a circus
что это не настоящий гет это цирковый
type because of this yes
типа из-за этого да
Well damn well I don't know but he is the most
Ну блин ну не знаю но он самый
adequate ruler of Ukraine like
адекватный правитель Украины как вот
look The thing is that here
смотри Дело в том что тут оценивать
now to evaluate whether Petliura was
сейчас там адекватный ли был Петлюра
adequate was Skoropadsky adequate further We are
адекватный был скоропадский дальше Мы
now evaluating them from the point of view of
сейчас их оцениваем с точки зрения уже
ours as we  we look at this whole story,
нашей как мы смотрим на эту всю историю
we are sitting here at home drinking coffee, they
мы тут сидим дома попивая кофе они
made the decision in the conditions that
принимали решение в тех условиях которые
were there with the resources that
там были с теми ресурсами которые там
were there, so it is also impossible to say that one is bad or
были поэтому говорить там тот плохой Или
that one is good, yes, they simply
тот хороший тоже нельзя да у них просто
had different concepts for the development of Ukraine,
были разные концепции развития Украины
so that one is more monarchical  ukraine-
так у то более монархическая украино
centric Petliura there more
центрическая у Петлюры там более
Socialist Ukraine was like this you
Социалистическая Украина была вот так
can say Vinichenko and so on that
можно сказать виниченко и так дальше то
is to say that this is only about
есть говорить что это только это насчёт
my thesis to say that this is Western
мой тезис говорить что это Западная
Ukraine it is anti-Russian And this Ukraine
Украина она антироссийская А это Украина
there is pro-Russian this is Soviet Tei this is
там пророссийская это Советский Тей это
Soviet y Ukraine Ukraine all and
Советский й Украина Украина вся и
always  considered itself the life of Russia that
всегда считала себя житний России что
without Ukraine Russia will die of hunger this
без Украины Россия сдохнет с голоду это
was the economy such a claim of Central
была экономи такая претензия Центральной
Ukraine and Western Ukraine taught the
Украина а Западная Украина учила
Habsburg monarchy that you will have to
монархия Габсбургов что вам придётся
fight bad they are schism they are
воевать плохие они схизма они
Orthodox  And you Uniates Greek Catholics do
православные А вы униаты греко-католики
you have the right religion Do you
у вас правильная религия Вы
like to look at these for the Uniates for the
любите смотри эти для для униатов для
Greeks
Грека
Yaks and Hungarians they are Catholics They
яки и венгри они католики Они вообще
were generally different it was not about that at all
другие были это там вообще не о том было
people who lived on the territory of the
люди которые жили на территории
Austro-Hungarian Empire in modern
австро-венгерской империи в современной
Ukraine Yes they were  in short, this
Украине Да им был короче этот
Austro-Hungarian emperor and
австро-венгерской император и его эти
all of them, they were also taken to
все вот их также типа брали типа на
war, that's
войну вот и
all, no, well, they still believed that
всё не ну там всё-таки там считали что и
Franz Joseph was there, something was different from Stalin
Франц Иосиф там что-то там не как Сталин
in the Soviet Union, the father of the people,
был в Советском Союзе там отец народа
everything  loved that is there No well there
его все любили то есть там Не ну такой
was such a Golan
был голан У
You have a writer E it is
вас писатель Э это
him
его его
they hammered him there 40 holes found with something it is
забили там 40 дырок нашли чем-то это
Communist Yes it is a commie it is a
Коммунистический Да это коммуни это
Communist traitor of Ukraine
Коммунистический предатель Украины
who this one contributed to
который вот этот способствовал
communist these falsifications
коммунистическим вот этим фальсификациям
described What bad Ukrainians are What
описывал Какие плохие украинцы Какие
bad Ukrainian nationalists Yes  and ukraine
плохие украинские националисты Да и укра
he wrote
он писал
that he was already a
что он уже был
greek catholic upbringing there
греко-католической воспитание там
let's say in western ukraine they took him to
допустим Западной Украине водили в
monasteries in catholic and catholic
монастыри в католические и католические
priests said that you have to love the
священники говорили что надо любить
emperor of Austria, Austria-Hungary and
императора Австрии австро-венгрии и
hate the Russian tsar, that they are there, they do
ненавидит русского царя что там они там
n't wash, they don't
такие-то там не моются там зубы не
brush their teeth, they walk around dirty and drunk, but you are
чистят грязные ходят пьяные А вот а вы
well
вот одетые хорошо
dressed and you should be,
одетые и вы должны быть Алю вот насчёт
look at this, absolutely truthfully  if if
этого смотри абсолютно правду если если
you look at the photographs of those
ты посмотришь да фотографии тех
territories of Ukraine that were under
территорий Украины которые были под
Austria-Hungary, there is Transcarpathia, there is
австро-венгрией там Закарпатья там
the Ivano-Frankivsk region, Lviv,
ивано-франковская область Львовская э
the beginning of the 20th century. Yes, you look at people
начало XX века Да ты посмотришь люди
dressed in normal clothes. Yes, shoes are
одетые в нормальных одеждах Да обувь
like leather. Well, that is, absolutely
типа кожная Ну то есть абсолютно
normal, and you are looking from the Russian
нормально и ты смотришь из Российской
Empire.  Yes, these
империи Да вот этих
bags on them are just some kind of Bag with
мешок на них тупо какой-то Мешок с
holes for the arms and
дырками под руки да
some kind of
какие-то
yuck what kind of Province do you understand damn someone
нят какая Губерния понимаешь блин кто-то
Rich someone poor again again
Богатый кто-то бедный ещё раз ещё раз
Look, right now they are posting a bunch of
Смотри я вот сейчас выкладывают куча
these archive photos Where in
фотографий вот этих архивных Где в том
that  with Austria Wenger there photography was
что с Австра Венгер там фотография была
very developed By the way, yes, there is also how
очень развита Кстати да вот есть и как
Czechoslovakia appeared, these people
Чехословакия появилась тоже вот эти
immediately Like started photography  they are all
сразу Типа начали фо все они все
normal,
нормально
all dressed normally, Ukrainians who
все нормально одеты украинцы которые
live here, there are Hutsuls and so on, they
живут вот эти Там гуцулы и так дальше у
all have normal clothes and shoes,
них всех одеж типа нормальные да обувь
they look normal, like
Нормально они выглядят как люди
civilized people, yes, if we look at the
цивилизованные Да если мы смотрим этот
same period, the Russian Empire, yes, they are
же период Российская империя Да они
like that, ragged, in some kind of burlap,
такие Оборванные в мешковина каких-то
you know  like Damn, they show how
знаешь как Блин вот это показывают как
a mammoth was eaten, like, and its skin
мамонта короче сожрали типа и шкур его
was pulled out really, and if
натянули реально и если такое
those in Austria-Hungary told such a story, that
рассказывали эти в австро-венгрии что
you are dressed and shod, and there are these
вот вы такие одетые обуты а там эти
barefoot ones Yes, it was true, it was true
голые босы Да это правда было это правда
Well, you know, maybe this is a selective photo
Ну знаешь может быть это выборочное фото
there x  you know Well what a selective photo so
там х зна Ну какое выборочное фото так
it's real it's the same as now you know that the
реально это так же как сейчас знаешь то
same thing Kursk province peasants are
то же самое Курская губерния крестьяне
dressed more there simply but it's not like
одеты более там просто но это не то что
burlap somehow somewhere there Vyatka
мешковины как-то вот где-то там Вятская
province but excuse me there are some
Губерния но извини там какие-то
factory workers there what  -they are
работники фабрики там какие-то теров ы
dressed in tailcoats with bow ties, they are
Они во фраках одет с бабочками
standing, that is, well, damn, I dont know how, how,
стоят то есть ну блин не знаю как как
for some reason, that is, look, Russia was
почему-то то есть смотри Россия
lagging behind  Austro-Hungarian Empire
отставала от австро-венгерской империи
Yes, by an order of magnitude, and the Austro-Hungarian
Да на порядок а австро-венгерская
Empire lagged behind the developed countries of
Империя отставала от развитых стран
Europe, also by an order of magnitude, from the same
Европы тоже на порядок от той же
Britain, simply Because when in
Британии просто Потому что когда в
Britain, uh, and trains were already And everything, yes,
Британии ээ и поезда уже И всё да
France Joseph was slowing down to the maximum This is
Франции Иосиф по максимуму тормозило Это
because Russia was also slowing down  the
потому что это и Россия также тормозила
railway because it would, let's say,
железную дорогу потому что это ээ скажем
promote the mobility of the population
способствовало бы мобильности населения
because both Austria, Hungary, and
потому что и Австрия Венгрия по сути и
Russia were essentially still holding on to the old, so to
Россия ещё держались за старые такие
speak, feudal order, in
можно сказать феодальные порядки
which, let's
которым
say, people were perceived as such a
скажем люди воспринимались как вот такой
local resource, that's all, Austria-Hungary
местный ресурс вот и всё австро-венгрия
jumped off this faster Yes, and  Russia
быстрее с этого спрыгнула Да а Россия
jumped off very, very late,
спрыгнула уже очень-очень позно везде
it was good everywhere, it was very hard everywhere and in
было хорошо везде было очень тяжело и в
England it was hard for the working class to live,
Англии было жить рабочему классу
I just recently watched this series
я вот я недавно смотрел Вот этот сериал
The Crown and all the fifties, sixties and
Корона и все пятидесятые шестидесятые
seventies of the reign of Elizabeth II
семидесятые года правление Елизаветы II
were spent in fear that the People
прошли во страхе того что Народ
would take up pitchforks and  axes and they will all be
возьмётся за вилы и за топоры и их всех
killed like the Romanovs and for them it was the
как Романовых перебьёт и для них это был
beginning of nightmares if something happened
нач кошмары если как что-то происходило
they  ran around the palace and said
они бегали по дворцу и приговариваю вот
God forbid a revolution happens we have to
не дай Бог случится революция надо
do something there are
делать есть
years when Cher their standard of living but
годах когда Чер их на уровень жизни но у
their standard of living is also falling now it has dropped
них сейчас тоже падает уровень жизни
very much like a squeak a comment and
очень сильно просел лайк писка комент и
send this video to your banner a letter on
скиньте Цей видос вашим знам пись на й
Telegram right now  axis VN and
Telegram прям зараз ось ВН а
pok ce very and very important YouTube is busy
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through scarg Orks in your ban and very
нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и дуже
many videos I dont show to people at times I dont
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about ST so that
показуе информация про СТ тому для того
we Mali operational links are written
щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
right now and while there is a video in telegram okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм вдео
more  also interesting and useful information and we are
ще теж цикава и корисна информация и ми
obliged to you
повинни з вами тримати
three times fast operational connection
постный оперативный звязок
independently in that will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава украини пись